Summoned to court to answer for the crime of your bannerman,
Gregor Clegane, The Mountain.
Arrive within a fortnight or be branded an enemy of the crown.
Poor Ned Stark. Brave man, terrible judgement.
Attacking him was stupid.
Lannisters
don't act like fools.
Are you gonna say something clever?
Go on, say something clever.
Catelyn Stark took my brother.
Why is he still alive?
Tyrion?
Ned Stark.
One of our men interfered...
speared him through the leg, before I could finish him.
Why is he still alive?
It wouldn't have been clean.
Clean?
You spend too much time
worrying about what other people think of you.
I could care less what what anyone thinks of me.
That's what you want people to think of you.
It's the truth.
When you hear them whispering "Kingslayer"
behind your back, doesn't it bother you?
Of course it bothers me.
The lion doesn't concern himself with the opinions of a sheep.
I suppose I should be grateful
that your varity got in the way of your reckelessnes.
I'm giving you half of our forces, 30000 men.
You will bring that to Catelyn Stark girlhood home,
and remind her that Lannisters pay their debts.
I didn't realize you place such a high value on my brother's life.
He's a Lannister.
He might be the lowest of the Lannister, but he's one of us.
And every day that he remain a prisoner
the less our name command respect.
So the lion does concern himself with the opinions of...
No, it's not an opinion. It's a fact.
If another house can seize one of our own
and hold him captive with impunity...
we are no longer house to be feared.
Your mother's dead.
Before long I'll be dead.
and you...
and your brother...
and your sister and all of her children...
All of us dead, all of us rotting in the ground.
Is the family name that lives on.
It's all that lives on.
Not your personal glory, not your honor, but family.
Do you understand?
You're blessed with abilities that few men possess.
You are blessed to belong to
the most powerful family in the kingdoms.
And you are still blessed with youth.
And what have you done with these blessings, huh?
You've served as a glorified bodyguard for two kings--
One a madman, the other a drunk.
The future of our family
will be determined in these next few months.
We could established a dinasty
that will last a thousand years.
Or we could collapse into nothing as, the Targaryens did.
I need you to become the man you were always meant to be.
Not next year, not tomorrow.
Now.
You're in pain.
I've had worse, my lady.
Perhaps it's time to go home.
The south doesn't seem to agree with you.
I knwo the truth Jon Arryn died for.
Do you, Lord Stark?
Is that why you called me here, to pose me riddles?
Has he done this before?
Jaime would have killed him.
My brother is worth a thousand of your friend.
Your brother...
or your lover?
The Targaryens wed brothers and sisters for 300 years
to keep bloodlines pure.
Jaime and I are more than brother and sister.
We shared a womb.
We came into this world together. We belong together.
My son saw you with him.
- Do you love your children? - With all my heart.
No more than I love mine.
And they're all Jaime's.
Thank the Gods.
In the rare event that Robert leaves his whores
for long enough to stumble drunk into my bed,
I finish him off in other ways.
In the morning, he doesn't remember.
You've always hated him.
Hated him?
I worshipped him.
Every girl in the Seven Kingdoms dreamed of him
but he was mine by oath.
And when I finally saw him on our wedding day in the Sept of Baelor
lean and fierce and black-bearded,
it was the happiest moment of my life.
Then that night he crawled on top of me, stinking of wine
and did what he did-- what little he could do--
and whispered in my ear "Lyanna".
Your sister was a corpse and I was a living girl
and he loved her more than me.
When the king returns from his hunts, I'll tell him the truth.
You must be gone by then-- you and your children.
I will not have their blood on my hands.
Go as far away as you can,
with as many men as you can.
Because wherever you go,
Robert's wrath will follow you.
And what of my wrath, Lord Stark?
You should have taken the realm for yourself.
Jaime told me about the day King's Landing fell.
He was sitting in the Iron Throne and you made him give it up.
All you needed to do was climb the steps yourself.
Such a sad mistake.
I've made many mistakes in my life,
but that wasn't one of them.
Oh, but it was.
When you play the game of thrones, you win or you die.
There is no middle ground.
No, No, No, No.
Is that what they teach you up in the North?
And you, wherever you're from.
Do you have any idea how ridiculous you sound?
Either of you understand a thing that I'm saying?
Yes, my lord.
Lets start over. Shall we?
You be the man, and you be the woman.
Well, go ahead.
Slowly.
You're not fooling them, they just paid you,
they know what you are.
They know its all just an act.
Your job is to make them forget what they know.
And that takes time.
You need to...
Ease into it.
Go ahead.
He's winding you over in spite of yourself.
You're starting to like this.
He wants to believe you.
He's enjoyed his cock since he was old enough
to play with it, shouldn't you?
He knows he's better than other men.
He's always known it deep down inside now he has proof.
He's so good.
He's reaching something deep inside of you
that no one even knew was there.
Overcoming your very nature.
Why don't you join us, my lord?
I'm saving myself for another.
What she doesn't know won't hurt her.
A stupid saying.
What we don't know is usually what get us killed.
She must be very beautiful.
No, not really. Impeccable bloodlines though.
I do believe my lord's in love.
For many years. Most of my life really.
Play with her ass.
And she loved me too.
I was her little confidant.
Her plaything. She could tell me anything, anything at all.
She told me about all the horses that she liked.
The castle that she want to live in.
And the man that she wanted to marry.
A northener.
With a jaw like an anvil.
So I challenged him to a duel.
I mean, why not? I'd read all the stories.
The little hero always beats the big villain in all the stories.
In the end, she wouldn't even let him kill me.
"He's just a boy", she said.
"Please don't hurt him".
So he gave me a nice little scar
to remember him by and off they went.
- Is she still married to him? - Oh, no.
He got himself killed before the wedding.
And she ended up with his brother,
an even more impressive specimen.
She loves him, I'm afraid.
And why wouldn't she, I mean?
Who could compare to him, he just so...
Good.
Do you know what I learned, losing that duel?
I learned that I'll never win.
Not that way. That's their game.
Their rules.
I'm not going to fight them.
I'm going to fuck them.
That's what I know, that's what I am.
And only by admitting what we are can we get what we want.
And what do you want?
Oh, everything, my dear.
Everything there is.
Now wash yourself, both of you are working tonight.
You're very lucky girl, do you know that?
Where I come from we don't show mercy to criminals.
Where I come from, if someone like you attacked a little lord.
At low tide we'd lay you on your back on the beach,
your hands and feet chained to four stakes.
Sea will coming closer and closer.
You'd see death creeping toward you a few inches at a time.
Where is it you come from?
The Iron Islands.
They far away?
You've never heard of the Iron Islands?
Trust me, you've never heard where I'm from neither.
Trust me, my lord.
You're not living in the wilderness anymore.
In civilised lands,
you refer to your betters by their proper titles.
And what's that?
Lord.
Why?
What do you mean "Why"?
My father is Balon Greyjoy, lord of the Iron Islands.
What's that got to do with you?
Your father's lord, how can you be lord too?
I will be lord after my father...
So you're not lord now.
No, you...
You having a go at me?
Is that it?
Just don't understand how you southerner do things.
I'm not a southerner.
You're from south of The Wall.
That make you southerner to me.
You're an impudent little wench, aren't you?
Couldn't say, my lord. Didn't know what impunent means.
Impudent. It means rude.
Disrespectful.
Do you want to lose that chain?
Theon Greyjoy!
The lady is our guest.
I thought she was our prisoner.
Are the two mutually exclusive in your experience?
Chances are I won't be nearby the next time that happens.
I'm used to worst than him.
I'm used to men tha who could chew that boy up.
And pick their teeth with his bones.
Why did you come here?
Didn't mean to come here.
Meant to get much further south than this.
As far south as south goes.
Before the long night comes.
Why?
What are you afraid of?
There's things that sleep in the day and hunt at night.
owls and shadowcats and...
I'm not talking about owls and shadowcats.
The things you speak of
they've been gone for thousands of years.
They weren't gone, old man.
They was sleeping.
And they ain't sleeping no more.
I miss girls.
Not even talking to them, I never talked to them.
Just looking at them,
Hearing them giggle.
Don't you miss girls?
Riders!
The horn. We have to blow the horn.
Why is he alone?
One blast for a ranger returning;
two for wildlings;
- three for... - There's no rider.
That's my uncle benjen's horse.
Where's my uncle?
Ned!
It's Robert...
We were hunting... a boar...
I should have spent more time with you,
shown you how to be a man.
I was never meant to be a father.
Go on...
You don't want to see this.
My fault...
Too much wine.
Missed my thrust.
Stinks.
It stinks like death.
Don't think I can't smell it.
I paid the bastard back, Ned.
I drove my knife right through his brain.
You ask them if I didn't. Ask them!
I want the funeral feast to be the biggest the kingdoms ever saw.
And I want everyone to taste the boar that got me.
Now leave us, the lot of you I need to talk to Ned.
- Robert, my sweet... - Out! All of you!
You damn fool.
Paper and ink. On the table.
Write down what I say.
In the name of Robert of the House Baratheon
First of... you know how it goes, fill in the damn titles.
I hereby command...
Eddard of House Stark... titles... titles...
to serve as Lord Regent
and Protector of The Realm, upon my death
to rule in my stead
until my son Joffrey comes of age.
Give it over.
Give it to the council
after I'm dead.
At least they'll say I did this right, this one thing.
You'll rule now.
You'll hate it worse than I did...
but you'll do it well.
The girl...
Daenerys...
you were right.
Varys, Littlefinger, my brother, worthless...
No one to tell me "No", but you.
Only you.
Let her live.
- Stop it, if it's not too late. - I will.
And my son...
help him, Ned.
Make him better than me
I'll...
I'll do everything I can to honor your memory.
My memory?
King Robert Baratheon...
murdered by a pig.
Give me something to the pain, and let me die.
Give him milk of the poppy.
He was reeling from the wine.
He commanded us to...
step aside, but...
I failed him.
No man could have protected him from himself.
I wonder, Ser Barristan, who gave the King this wine?
His squire. From the King's own skin.
His squire? The Lannister boy?
Such a dutiful boy to
make sure His Grace did not lack refreshment.
I do hope the poor lad is not blame himself.
His Grace has had a change
of heart concerning Daenerys Targaryen.
Whatever arrangements you made...
unmade them, at once.
I'm afraid those birds have flown.
The girl is likely dead already.
Throne.
Can't you help me make him understand?
The Dothraki do things on their own time, for their own reason.
Have patience, Khaleesi. We will go home, I promise you.
My brother...
was a fool, I know,
but he was the rightful heir to the Seven Kingdoms.
Have I said something funny, ser?
Forgive me, khaleesi, but your ancestor, Aegon The Conqueror,
didn't seize six of the kingdoms because it's his right.
He had no right to them, he seized them because he could.
And because he had dragons.
Ah well, having few dragons makes things easier.
You don't believe it?
Have you ever seen a dragon, khaleesi?
I believe what my eyes and ears report.
As for the rest, it was 300 years ago,
who knows what really happened.
Now if you pardon me, I'll seek out the merchant captain,
- See if he has any letters for me. - Well, I'll come with you.
No, no, don't trouble yourself.
Enjoy the market. I'll rejoin you soon enough.
Psst, Jorah the Andal.
The Spider sent his greetings and his congratulations.
A royal pardon--
you can go home now.
My son already has his name,
but I'll try your summerwine. Just a taste.
My lady, you are from Westeros?
You have the honor of addressing Daenerys of the House Targaryen.
Khaleesi of the riding men,
and princess of the Seven Kingdoms.
- Princess. - Rise.
I still like to taste that wine.
That?
Dorne's swill, not worthy of a princess.
I have the dry red from the Arbor.
Nectar of the Gods.
Let me give you a cask.
- A gift! - You honor me, Ser.
The honor... the honor is all mine.
You know there are many in your homeland
that pray for your return, princess.
I hope to repay your kindness someday.
Rakharo.
Is something wrong?
I have a thirst. Open it.
The wine is for the Khaleesi, it's not for the likes of you.
Open it.
Pour.
It would be a crime to drink a wine this rich
without at least giving it time to breathe.
Do as he says.
As the princess command.
Sweet, isn't it?
Can you smell the fruit, Ser?
Taste it, my lord.
Tell me that is not the
finest wine that has ever touch your tongue.
You first.
Me?
I'm afraid I'm not worthy of the vintage.
Beside, is it a poor wine merchant who drink up his own wares.
You will drink.
- Khaleesi! - Stop him!
Come.
You came to us as outlaws.
poachers,
rapers,
killers, thieves.
You came alone,
in chains,
without friends, nor honor.
You came to us rich,
or you came to us poor.
Some of you bear the name of proud houses,
others only bastard names or no names at all.
It does not matter. All that, is in the past.
Here...
on the Wall.
we're all one house.
Tonight...
You're allowed to look happy,
you're going to be a ranger.
Isn't that what you always wanted?
I want to find my uncle.
I know he's alive out there. I know he is.
I wish I could help you, but I'm no ranger.
It's the steward's life for me.
There's honor in being a steward.
Not much, really.
But there's food.
Here,
you begin anew.
A man of the Night's Watch,
lives his life for the realm.
Not for a king,
or a Lord,
or the honor of this house or that house.
Not for gold nor glory
or women's love.
But for the realm
and all the people in it.
You've all learned the words of the vow.
Think carefully before you say them.
The penalty for desertion
is death.
You can take your vows here...
tonight...
at sunset.
Do any of you still keep the Old Gods?
I do, my lord.
Do you want to take your vows
before the heart tree, as your uncle did?
Yes, my lord.
You'll find the weirwoods, a mile north of the Wall
and your Old Gods too, maybe.
My Lord?
Might I go as well?
Is House Tarly keep the Old Gods?
No, my lord.
I was name in the light of the Seven,
as my father was and his father before him.
Why would you forsake,
the Gods of your father and your house?
The Night's Watch is my house now.
The Seven have never answer my prayers,
perhaps the Old Gods will.
As you wish, lad.
You all been assigned an order,
according to our needs,
and your strength.
Halder to the builders.
Pyp to the stewards.
Tod to the builders.
Grenn to the rangers.
Samwell to the stewards.
Matthar to the rangers.
Dareon to the stewards.
Balian to the rangers.
Rast to the rangers.
Jon to the stewards.
Rancer to the builders.
Echiel to the builders. Gordo to the stewards.
Niko to the rangers. Escan to the rangers.
Vorkoy to the builders. Joby to the stables.
Mink to the kitchens.
Allo to the builders.
Nelugo to the rangers.
May all the Gods preserve you.
Rangers, with me.
Builders!
Samwell,
you will assisst me in the rookery and the library.
Pyp,
you will report to Bowen Marsh, in the kitchens.
Luke, report to one-eyed Joe in the stables.
Dareon, we are sending you to Eastwatch.
present yourself to Borcas when you arrive.
Make no comment about his nose.
Jon Snow,
Lord Commander Mormont
has requested you for his personal steward.
Will I serve the Lord Commander's meal,
and fetch hot water for his bath?
Certainly.
And keep a fire burning in his chambers,
change his sheets and blankets daily
and do everything else the Lord Commander requires of you.
Do you take me for a servant?
We took you for a man of the Night's Watch.
But perhaps we were wrong in that.
May I go?
As you wish.
Jon, Wait!
Don't you see what they're doing?
I see Ser Alliser's revenge, that's all.
he wanted it and he got it.
Stewards are nothing but maids!
I'm a better swordsman and rider than any of you!
It's not fair!
Fair?
I was singing for a high lord at Acorn Hall
when he put his hand in my leg
and he wanted to see my cock.
I pushed him away and he said
he'd have my hands cut off for stealing their silver.
So now I'm here, at the end of the world
where no one to sing for but old men and little shits like you.
I'll never see my family again.
I'll never be inside a woman again.
So don't tell me about fair.
I thought you were caught stealing a wheel of cheese
for your starving sister?
You think I was gonna tell a bunch of strangers
that a high lord tried to grab my cock?
Could you sing me a song, Pyp?
I'd like to hear a song.
Now listen to me,
the old man is the Lord Commander of The Night's Watch.
You will be with him day and night,
yes, you will clean his clothes.
But you will also take his letters,
attend him at meeting, squire for him in battle.
You'll know everything, be part of everything.
And he asked for you himself.
He wants to groom you for command.
I just...
I always wanted to be a ranger.
I always wanted to be a wizard.
What?
No, I'm serious.
So you'll stay and say your words with me?
Lord Stark,
a moment?
Alone if you will.
He named you Protector of The Realm.
He did.
She won't care.
Give me an hour and I can put a hundred of swords at your command.
- And what should I do with a hundred swords? - Strike!
Tonight while the castle sleeps.
We must get Joffrey away from his mother and into our custody.
Protector of The Realm or no,
he who holds the king holds the kingdom.
Every moment you delay gives Cersei another moment to prepare.
By the time Robert dies, it will be too late for the both of us.
What about Stannis?
Saving the Seven Kingdoms from Cersei
and delivering them to Stannis?
You have odd notion about "protecting the realm".
Stannis is your older brother.
This isn't about the bloody line of succession.
That didn't matter when you rebelled against the Mad King
it shouldn't matter now.
What's best for the kingdoms?
What's best for the people we rule?
We all know what Stannis is.
He inspires no love or loyalty.
He's not a king.
I am.
Stannis is a commander.
He's led men into war twice.
He destroyed the Greyjoy fleet...
Yes, he's a good soldier, everyone knows that.
So was Robert.
Tell me something: Do you still believe
good soldiers make good kings?
I will not dishonor Robert's last hours
by shedding blood in his halls
and dragging frightened children from their beds.
You will sail to Dragonstone tonight.
You will place this in the hand of Stannis Baratheon.
Not his steward.
Not his captain of the guard.
And not his wife.
Only Stannis himself.
Yes, my lord.
Now leave us.
My lord protector.
The king has no trueborn sons.
Joffrey and Tommen are Jaime Lannister's bastards.
So when the king dies...
The throne passes to his brother
Lord Stannis.
So it would seem.
- Unless... - There is no "unless"!
He is the rightful heir. Nothing can change that.
And he cannot take the throne without your help.
You would be wise to deny it to him
and to make sure Joffrey succeeds.
Do you have a shred of honor?
You're now Hand of The King and Protector of The Realm,
all the power is yours, you need only...
reach out and take it.
Make peace with the Lannisters. Release The Imp.
Wed your daughter to Joffrey.
We have plenty of time to get rid of Stannis
and if Joffrey seems likely
to cause problems when he comes into his throne,
we simply reveal his little secret
- and seat Lord Renly there instead. - We?
You'll need someone to share these burdens, I assure you,
my price would be modest.
What you suggest is treason.
Only if we lose.
Make peace with the Lannisters, you say...
with the people who tried to murder my boy.
We only make peace with our enemies, my lord.
That's why it's called "Making peace".
No.
I won't do it.
- So it will be Stannis and war? - There is no other choice.
He is the heir.
So why did you call me here? Not for my wisdom, clearly.
You promised Catelyn you would help me.
The queen has a dozen knights and hundred man-at-arms.
Enough to overwhelm what remains of my household guard.
I need the Gold Cloaks.
The City Watch is 2,000 strong,
and sworn to defend the king's peace.
Look at you.
You know what you want me to do, you know it has to be done.
But it's not honorable so
the words stick in your throat.
When the Queen proclaims one king
and the Hand proclaim another,
whose peace to the Gold Cloaks protect?
Who do they follow?
The man who pays them.
Hear my words and bear witness to my vow.
Night gathers and now my watch begins.
It shall not end until my death.
I shall take no wife, hold no lands, father no children.
I shall wear no crowns and win no glory.
I shall live and die at my post.
I am the sword in the darkness.
I am the watcher on the walls.
I am the shield that guards the realm of men.
I pledge my life and honor to the Night's Watch,
for this night and all the nights to come.
You knelt as boys.
Rise now as men of the Night's Watch.
- Well done. - Well done.
What's he got there?
To me, Ghost.
Bring it here.
Gods be good!
What will they do to him?
When the khalasar rides,
he'll be leashed to a saddle and
forced to run behind the horses for as long as he can.
And when he falls?
I saw a man last nine miles once.
King Robert still wants me dead.
This poisoner was the first. He won't be the last.
I thought he'd leave me alone, now that my brother is gone.
He will never leave you alone.
If you ride to darkest Asshai, his assassins will follow you.
If you sail all the way to the Basilisk Isles,
his spy would tell him.
He will never abandon the hunt.
You are a Targaryen.
The last Targaryen.
Your son will have Targaryen blood
with 40,000 riders behind him.
He will not have my son.
He will not have you either, Khaleesi.
Lord Stark!
- Stop! - No, all right.
- It's all right. Let him through. - Lord Stark,
King Joffrey and the Queen Regent
request you presence in the throne room.
King Joffrey?
King Robert is gone. The Gods give him rest.
All is accomplished. The City Watch is yours.
Good.
Is Lord Renly joining us?
I fear Lord Renly has left the city.
He rode through the Old Gate an hour before dawn
with ser Loras Tyrell and some 50 retainers.
Last seen galloping south in some haste.
We stand behind you, lord Stark.
All hail His Grace, Joffrey of Houses Baratheon and Lannister,
the First of His Name,
King of The Andals, and The First Men,
Lord of The Seven Kingdoms and Protector of The Realm.
I command the council to make
all necessary arrangements for my coronation.
I wish to be crowned within the fortnight.
Today I shall accept oaths of fealty from my loyal councilors.
Ser Barristan,
I believe no men here could ever question your honor.
King Robert seal.
Unbroken.
Lord Eddard Stark is herein named
Protector of The Realm,
to rule as regent
until the heir come of age.
May I see that letter, ser Barristan?
Protector of The Realm.
Is this meant to be your shield, Lord Stark?
A piece of paper?
Those were the king's words.
We have a new king now.
Lord Eddard, when we last spoke you offered me some counsel.
Allow me to return the courtesy.
Bend the knee, my lord.
Bend the knee and swear loyalty to my son.
And we shall allow you to live out your days in the grey waste
you call home.
Your son has no claim to the throne.
Liar!
You condemn yourself with your own mouth, lord Stark.
Ser Barristan, seize this traitor.
Ser Barristan is a good man, a loyal man. Do him no harm.
You think you stands alone?
Kill him! Kill all of them! I command it!
Commander!
Take the queen and her children into custody.
Escort them back to the royal apartments
and keep them there, under guard.
Men of the watch!
I want no bloodshed.
Tell your men to lay down their swords. No one needs to die.
Now!
I did warn you not to trust me.